SHANNON CHU

shannonchu.github.io / shannonchu@berkeley.edu / 323-712-8742

SUMMARY

Fuses a background in human cognition and design to deliver creative solutions and meaningful experiences. Works well with both digital and physical mediums and utilizes user-centered research to bring ideas to life. Excels at transforming complex information into strong visual designs and meeting deadlines in quick-turnaround settings.

EDUCATION

2012 - 2016

University of California, Berkeley BA Cognitive Science

Emphasis in Human-Centered Design

SKILLS

Design

Mockups / Branding / Layout / Interaction Usability / Research / Testing

Tools

InDesign / Illustrator / Photoshop / Sketch Omnigraffle / SolidWorks / SketchUp

Development

HTML / CSS / Ruby on Rails / JavaScript / Python

Fabrication

Prototyping / Laser Cutting / 3D Printing Soldering / operating machinery

EXPERIENCE

JUNE 2015 - DEC 2016

UX Design Intern – UC Berkeley | Berkeley, CA

- Assisted the UX team in transforming the online experiences of 35,000+ students with UC Berkeley's Student Information Systems replacement project.
- Mapped the class planning & enrollment journey to convey student values to campus stakeholders.
- Designed a class schedule sharing tool to increase course discovery and help students connect.
- Established a student advisory group to solicit feedback and inform design decisions.
- Delivered designs to improve advising tools based on insights from research and user testing.

MAY - JUNE 2015

Design Intern – Justman Packaging & Display | Commerce, CA

- Crafted 3D models of product packaging and displays from 2D nets.
- Produced dielines and instructional materials for display and packaging assembly.

JUNE - AUG 2014

Tools and Infrastructure Improvement Intern – XEROX | El Segundo, CA

- Created and automated VM build scripts, performance tests, and code change reports.
- Produced stylesheets for build and test results for quicker review of the data.

JAN 2013 - DEC 2014

Senior Layout Designer – The Daily Californian | Berkeley, CA

- Designed layouts 8 graphics for news, opinion, arts 8 entertainment, sports and special issues.
- Attended daily budget meetings to discuss and determine content and direction.

DEC 2013 - MAY 2014

Design Editor – The Daily Californian | Berkeley, CA

- Oversaw a team of 27 layout designers, graphic artists, and illustrators.
- Implemented a position that streamlined production & increased visual content in the publication.
- Managed, edited, and approved design content on a daily 5 p.m. print deadline.
- Served on the Senior Editorial Board to discuss high-level editorial and business decisions.

JUNE - AUG 2013

Graphic Design Intern - Ready Artwork | San Gabriel, CA

- Collaborated with the graphics team on branding, advertising, and web projects.
- Created wireframes and styleguides to support the development team.

PROJECTS

SEPT 2015 - MAY 2016

Project Developer – Cal Blueprint

Built a social platform in 12 weeks for Ashby Village, a Bay Area nonprofit that helps senior citizens connect with each other and with the resources they need to remain active and independent. Built with a team of five engineers as a part of Cal Blueprint, a student group that builds mobile and web apps for non-profits pro bono.

JAN 2015 - MAY 2015

Product Designer – TENSOS

In a project sponsored by the Tensegrity Robotics division at NASA, I worked with an interdisciplinary team of engineering and business students to develop a tensegrity toy building kit from initial idea to finished product for educational outreach and to foster interest in STEM fields in K-8 age children.